Okay.  And now we continue on to Auna.   Are
you ready?
I said
a thing about a man in
the
dark
and my A was like a 90 that
was only
60% A and it was an A that was pretty
stupid.
And okay, Nagatuna said to the
other person, "So you're criticizing me?"
within nothingness.  Why count it as zero?  It
means nothingness and the absence of anything,
but the Four Noble Truths and all
other things.  Are you finished?  And you
and I, I've included everything, and
you're not a Buddhist.  And
Nagatuna would say that if you think emptiness
means these things, then you have no purpose,
you have no essence, you have no point of emptiness,
and you have no purpose, you have no essence, you
have no
core essence of the point of emptiness
.
And then the rest of
this chapter and he and
you
explained these things and I
think because you don't have anything to
do today and you can find
these three things and I want to hear
your opinions
tomorrow and tell me that you don't
understand the purpose of
emptiness, you don't understand the
nature of emptiness and you don't understand
the main point of emptiness and
how to distinguish
these essences.  And I want to
see what you all
think.  Okay.  And we also have Mr. Kitty
from 400 years
later.  And neither we nor they know
what his true purpose is.  And I'm very curious
what you all think?  What do you think?
And maybe you could cook it
today in your cabin retreat.  Okay.
And please, cook it, cook it during
your period of quiet retreat.  Okay.
And we'll talk about this
tomorrow.  Okay
?   Okay
.  Oh, we have two translation classes tomorrow
.
Occasionally the
organizers and I would... and okay, teacher, could you move
these two classes?  And I
said no.  These are the classes that have already
been scheduled weekly
.  And if you want to, why
don't you move your program
?  Okay.  And I said, "
Move, move your program
."  And these translations are a
chapter, a part of the
program
.  Okay.  And now we move on to the next verse
.  And the
truth is, I was asked
the deepest questions in the toilet,
and I tried to do
my job, and it was okay.  And people always want to
ask if it's okay.  And people are always asking
me questions.  And I just had
this question here.  In the
toilet, and if you
guys... and this is my answer,
and I told her...  Okay, now I'll
answer.  Essentially, this verse is
said to represent the Buddha's use of both realities when teaching the Dharma
.  What are the two realities
?  Is
reality the ultimate reality or an
indirect reality?
And the Buddha needed both of
these realities.  You can't say that the
Buddha spent all his time just
looking at glasses, and that's not the
case.  Okay.  They need
emerging realities and
ordinary realities, and
they use ordinary realities,
and they also use
ultimate realities, and they balance
those two realities.
continua, and I think
he answered this question in
this verse, the eighth verse
in the next chapter 24, and he said
that you need
both.  I think we've seen those
peaks of someone who just
uses ordinary reality and
they just make money and they just work hard
and they just take care of their family and they
just take care of their children and
that's all they do
and then
they collapse because it's impermanent.  Okay.
The children grow up and the
children die and the jobs are lost
and the businesses collapse
and it gets even worse if
you succeed and then you
die and nothing
more than this and
everything has to collapse, everything
is a problem and this is
just normal reality.  This is normal reality
.  And in
another case, you do a retreat at
Diamond Mountain and you learn about
emptiness and you learn about
these classics and you sit in one of
your five houses and
you have a part of
these things.  You need to have a
life, and you can make that
life even better.  And I
don't think you can, and don't
think you can't, make this
amazing and beautiful.
And I've had a few of my students
.  Okay.  And not only did I
have 50 years to be exhausted by
my own students, but I also
exhausted them for 25 years.
And I had so many
students who gave up, and they came to
my teacher and said, '
Okay, I'm going to stop working, and
I'm going to live a free life
.'  And my teacher said, "And
we lived in New
Jersey, in a
very small town, and there was a little forest
next to the
town. And he said, 'Okay, and I'll go
to the forest.'"
And my teacher was okay, there was
autumn in New Jersey
and winter was coming in New Jersey,
and before global warming
we had things called
snow, and we talked about
about three or four years' worth of hits, so the snow was
high, you know,
and I gave up the
business, and it was impermanent. And I have a
family and all
these normal things, and I'm going to go into the woods, and
you know.  And then,
just two weeks later, he came back and
he sat in the kitchen and ate
everything in the refrigerator.  And
you know, he
said that in the forest there are no
refrigerators.  And ultimately, they come from what's
called money.  And all of
these are called the things you
have to do at work.  Okay.  You need
both.  You need both.  Na Guna said
that you need both.  You need
to experience both ordinary reality and
ultimate reality.  And reality and substance are these
two realities; they support each
other.  Okay.  And you need to have
decent jobs.  You need to have a
good income and don't go
crazy.  Okay.  Don't go crazy and act
like you're working 18 hours a
day.  Every job in
this universe creates something that
people want, and that's why they
pay you.  And then those
things will help everyone.  And if
you build houses, if you
can make refrigerators, and if
you can
manufacture cars, it will help
people.
Uh, and there were capitalists, and he
built houses, he built
houses all around me, and
I was always afraid to
introduce him to my teacher,
and one day they finally
met, and I was very embarrassed when
my wife was here, knowing my father,
and my wife came, and she was
only about 16 years old at the time, and we spent
time together, and he was a
capitalist.
And my father and my teacher
sat together in a
kitchen inside a small
Mongolian temple in New Jersey.  And
my teacher's father looked at my father and said, "
I hear you're a
big businessman, and you've built
houses, you've built towns,
right?"  Okay.  And my father was right,
and my teacher said, "Oh, that's a
wonderful Dharma practice," and
he said, "Okay, you
're bringing many families a
place to live, and you're like a
Bodhisattva."  Okay.  And I was
like, "Oh, what's going on
?"  And then my father said that
he had previously hoped
I would become a missionary,
but now he thinks
it's a good thing that I've become a
Buddhist.
And in this poem,
Nagasuna says that we need
both.  And there's a point of contention that you
've made here, and it's quite fascinating.  And
he said that when the Buddha taught
you about emptiness in the garden of
retirement or
when he taught the Paramita Heart Sutra, did he
use language, did he
use words, did
he write it down, or did
someone else write down
the
Prajnaparamita Sutra?
It doesn't say it's not the
ultimate reality; it is reality, it is ordinary reality
.
The words, the books, the
teachings, the translations, and
the programs at Diamond
Mountain are all
normal realities, and you go
there and eat, and I
hope someone pays for
these things, and there's a student, and
my sponsor, and
this student center is
sponsored by a very, very
kind person. When I first met him,
Mr. Ok.  And I said that
I think it's about $100,000
.  And I thought it would be
around $200,000, and in the end it
came down to $1.2 million to build
this student center.  And I had to go
to him.  And in the end,
he did pay for
these things.  Okay.  And during this week
you should thank Dr.  Go.  And
we are very grateful to Dr.  Go.
Oh, would you like to hear a secret
?  I need to have an
interpreter so I can talk to
him.
And there was a woman in Guangzhou who
said I would
translate for her.  And then she started, "Oh, we have
a
retreat center and we
need a place to go, a place to eat," and he
started crying, and then the
sponsors were like, "Okay, we
need money, you need money,
right?"  And that's shopping.  And in the
end, he paid for
it.  And that's the
battery.  Okay.  And anyway, you need
both.  Okay.  You need a
construction company to build these
hideouts.  And thank God
these people aren't
French students; they can build
themselves up.
And that is what Gaduna said in
this poem.  You need both;
you need organizations, you need to be
there building structures,
you need to have books there, and
you need money to do the work, and
they go
together.  And it's not that the business has to
be dirty, but the
business has to be shady, it has to be secretive,
and we've talked about that already.  And that
business can be a treasure trove of diamonds
if you approach it
with the right mindset; it's
an unimaginable achievement
.  And you must have that kind of
mindset.  And in fact, what
you need are
deceptive realities
.  Deceptive realities mean
ordinary realities; you
need to recognize ordinary realities
in order to learn the
ultimate realities. You need both.  You
need both of them to go together.
And who created this?  That is the
Buddha.  When the Buddha taught the Dharma, he needed
both; he needed both.  And there's someone who
needs to pay for the electricity and air
conditioning.  You know...  And they and
you need
both.  Okay.  I apologize for a
moment.  Okay.  What is the next picture,
guys?  Okay.
Lord Naruna said you need
balance.  You need to find a balance
between the deceptive reality, the ordinary reality,
and the ultimate reality
.  And people say that I have, I have,
I have the verses of the
master.  Those words are the
ultimate deception of reality, and they
are not the ultimate realities.  These are the
ultimate causes, the
ultimate causes and effects
.  And without emptiness,
you cannot attain
nirvana.  You cannot teach Dharma with
words if you don't have
words.  But words are
not the ultimate reality.  They are
just normal realities.  You
need to experience normal realities
.  You need to experience
false realities in order to reach the
true
reality.  But Mr. Nagasuna has some very,
very famous rhymes and lines
.
Okay, tell me
what your real position is
.  And I think that's what the
farmers
believe.  Okay.  And I believe in everything
that farmers believe.   The
next picture.  The photo is a bit
strange.  I tried.  I really
tried very, very hard
.  It took half an hour of
negotiation with AIA to get this photo.
A woman who had
jewelry with snakes wrapped
around her head.
I tried 20 times for this photo.
But this is the best thing that can happen
.  If that sounds a little strange, I
apologize.  Do I need to spend
another hour cleaning?  No, I don't need it
anymore.  And this is the verse he spoke of
when people have no respect for
emptiness
and when they say emptiness is
foolish.
Or maybe I don't, and I don't see
anything about
emptiness, and how would it help you to
think about things that are
vast and they say I don't understand, and
when they speak ill of
emptiness, and they are
broken, and then you have an example
from ancient times, if you
want, in ancient times it was believed
that every venomous snake had a
jewel in the middle, like a ruby
.
And and if they say that if
someone doesn't respect the idea
of ​​emptiness, or
someone is trying to learn about emptiness
without understanding it, they're like
someone looking for a venomous snake
and trying to pull the stake out of the
snake's cup, and
eventually they will
die. And everything that Ayan said is deeper
and always has
deeper meanings
.  And all he said was that
learning about emptiness is dangerous and it's
like a cobra.  If only
you could take nothingness
out of the snake's head
.  Okay.  And the name Nagasuna
means "king of
snakes."
King of cobras,
and by the way, Xuanzang
walked for 17 years across 51
Asian countries to spread Buddhism to China, specifically to Chang'an during the
Tang Dynasty. There were people who wanted to kill
him, and
he visited a great library
in South India. I think that was a
past life of John Fendy, like
AOL
.  And Nagatuna was a
book collector, like the AL of
his time.  He collected
ancient books and had a great library
in South India. He thought it was
important to preserve these
books, and he devoted all his time
to preserving them. He tried his best to preserve these books,
and he
built the library. Xuanzang
went to
that library, brought back books, and that's how
Buddhism began to appear in
China.  And
we have heard of some lost books
in
this world.  And those people and those
dragons, we like precious things,
and it's like it's special,
like gold or diamonds
.
And these dragons try to
hide, try to collect
these and sit on top of them to make
sure that no one uses
these books.  And Nagasuna heard that the
dragons had
texts that they brought back to their homes,
and he learned how to
talk to the dragons and
became a master.  The master of
these dragons.  Master means
Arjuna.
And those great archers,
and he became a
master, a master of dragons,
and he collected
these books
from the Naga worlds of
dragons, and he brought them back to
this world, and he knew how to approach
these dangerous snakes to
take the jewels from their foreheads
.  Okay.  Do you understand?   Okay
.  And when he mentions it here, you
can understand the context,
this history.  And then he said that emptiness is
like those storm jewels
on the heads of dragons,
on the foreheads of
dragons.  And when you approach
venomous snakes, it's very dangerous, and there's a
chance you'll
get bitten, which is very dangerous at that moment.
And
why is Nagona talking about this?
And everyone doesn't know what they're
doing about
emptiness, and they just say emptiness is okay, so
close your eyes.  H h
h everything in Chinese means pitch
black, pitch black, pitch black
.  It's like you close your
eyes and don't think about
anything at all.  Do you understand?
If you try to learn about
emptiness from people who don't
understand what emptiness is, you will be bitten
by that emptiness.
And you will be deceived about nothingness, and
you will spend your whole life
sitting staring at a wall and
thinking about what nothing is.  Think about nothing
.  And then you will be poisoned.
You will be
poisoned, and you will spend your whole life
working at a gas station, and your whole life
just sitting there, staring at the
wall, and thinking about nothing,
nothing at all.  And that is the
ultimate waste of a human life
.  And he said they would be
hurt.  And he gave an
example of something in the
Senrit language called Darani, which is called a
mantra, the mantras of the
Buddha, and he said that people
used these mantras without
knowing what they were doing and they got
bitten.
One Hel mentioned yesterday that if
you truly love the
practice of Medicine Buddha.   Okay
.  There's an essay in the
book that explains
how effective mnemonic devices work
.  And if you don't know how to
perform the incantations, then
these incantations won't be effective for the people you're helping.
To practice those incantations and
then die of cancer is
a very troublesome thing
.  And Nag aya A Nagatuna said that
you need to have emptiness to understand the
mantras and understand man.  You need to
have
emptiness, and you need to have
emptiness wisely and
carefully.
And if you don't
ask the snakes in Arizona to
give you the jewels on their
heads without
careful consideration, you will get hurt,
you will get hurt
.  And he said that those
who learn about emptiness in the wrong way
will be hurt, they will be
wounded.  Okay, you can imagine
that, right?
Okay, I'm sorry, I have 1200 pages of
notes
here.  Wait a
minute.  What is the next picture,
guys?
What number?
Which picture is it?  I'll tell you the number of
that picture.   Okay
.  Wait a minute
.  6.10.
What are 6.11 and 6.10
?  Okay.  6.1.
Okay, this image is
fine.  I made a mistake because I
'm writing
DCI courses to find
modern images that can represent
older images,
okay?  This represents the Buddha.
The Buddha hesitated to teach,
hesitating for seven
weeks, and he attained enlightenment, and he
refused to teach for seven
weeks.  And this is the meaning
this image represents.  Do you understand?
It's like a professor
sitting in a
classroom and not feeling comfortable enough to
teach.  And
in this chapter, Auna said
that the Buddha had realized, had
understood.  If he hadn't taught the concept of
emptiness carefully, people would
have misunderstood it.  And I thought that
for the past thousand years people have
misunderstood the concept of
nothingness.  Okay.  And I listened most of the time
.  I've heard things from
strange people and they say that being oblivious
doesn't mean
you should try to think about nothing at all.
Oh, there's no problem at
all.  Everything is empty.  It's like
that.
Why do you think this picture is
related to
that?  To reiterate, to
reiterate, it means that Ayan
Nagatuna is admitting that nothingness is
very difficult, very difficult.  And then you ask,
why do you think the Buddha sat there
without saying anything for seven weeks?
He was afraid that not everyone would
misunderstand, but that they would
misinterpret it. He thought it best
not to talk about it, and it was very profound.
This is the nature of emptiness, and
Nagatuna was the
greatest explainer of emptiness in history, considered the
second Buddha.
He thought that the
Buddha hesitated because it
would be very dangerous if people
misunderstood emptiness. He thought that the
Buddha refused to teach it, and he felt that the
Buddha's sacred heart hesitated
to
speak because he feared that people would
misunderstand, especially that they would say
everything is empty and
what can I do? And I don't need to be kind
to people.  And you know,
everything is hollow.  I do
n't need to do anything.  And he was afraid
people would misunderstand.  And that is
why he refused.  He refused to teach
from the
start.  And Nagasuna said to
that man, "That's
why the Buddha didn't teach, did
n't say, 'Do you understand?'"  Do you understand
?
People like you are precisely the
reasons why the Buddha rejected the concept of
emptiness.  And if I had to choose one
verse from the 40 verses of
this chapter, and it were called the
examination of the truth of the Four
Noble Truths...
And if I had to choose the
most famous poem, this one would be it
.
My teacher
kept notes
and it kept coming back as a kind of
approach, and when I wrote
introductions to Mn's books, I
could clearly state
what the most famous Nagatuna [music] was and what had been
used in the last 2000 years
.  What are the top 10 things that
I've checked, and you can
check too, and I've done it.  I
did strange things like this
in Peru in a cafe with
Stanley.  This is one of
Nagatuna's most famous poems.
This is one of the top 10
most famous poems by Nagatuna.  If
everything is true and nothing
is true, then nothing is true
for everything.
If you think nothing fits everything,
then nothing will fit
it, just like a
pair of underwear.
If it's not
empty, then everything is
fine.  If it's not hollow, it
's a
disaster.  Nothing works without the absence of
zero
.  Calculation doesn't automatically mean everything will
work.  If it
doesn't resist emptiness, it won't be
effective.  Okay.  Let's talk about
pants.  Okay.  These examples are
simple and 100% correct.  And if
you don't think I built
a billion-dollar business
by accident, is that even possible?
What is the dependence of this pen?  What does it really mean
?  It simply means that everything comes
from the seed in your mind.
That's all.  Okay.  I've read
long, long, long books about
Buddhism, and they're all connected, and
you know, pla, and it doesn't make
sense, and what's the root dependency?
Everything comes from the seeds in
your minds.  It's as simple as that
.  It stems from how you
treat other people.
That's okay.  That's
all.  That underlying dependency is okay.
Don't worry about anything.   Okay
.  Did this pen come from the factory,
or did it come from G. Michael's mind
?  It comes from the seed in
your minds.  Okay.  And the
producers also come from the seeds
in your minds.  That's
dependence.  Okay.  And what is the nature of
this pen?  Give me $1000.
$1000.  And you can't raise your hand
before I ask the question.  Okay.
One question is worth
$1,000.   Okay
.  $1000.  The $1,000 question.   Okay
.  What is the best way to teach
emptiness to a large group of people
?  Okay.  Raise your hand
.  Okay.  The Diamond Vehicle of Buddhism is hidden.
Secret Buddhism.  Okay.  Okay?  For the
rest of your lives, if
you want to teach about non-duality, is that okay
?  Okay.  Everyone raise your hands,
raise your left hand and point.  Okay.  And
this little finger, okay? Don't
use your middle finger
.  Especially in Arizona, they have guns, so
don't use the middle finger
.  Okay.  And point to one thing in
this room that didn't come from a seed
in your mind
.  Oh, you can't do it like this,
you have to do it like this.   Okay
.  And don't forget what you need to
do, and what you need to do in the same way
.  You have to do it exactly like this
.  And that is nothingness.  That's all.
That is an imperfection.  That is,
being taught about
imperfection.  Why is that?  So why
are you angry with your husband?   Okay
.  There's an old joke about Diamond
Mountain that I'll tell
you about.  There was a man who forgot about it
about 10 years
ago.  Ten years ago, nobody here was
in that group.  One person, one
OK.  There was a new person, someone who
came to Diamond Mountain after the
lecture, and they were always complaining.  They
always complain about the diamond mountain representation
and how difficult it is.  We
have nothing, you know.
And they were always complaining and they came
and they said I was surrounded by
stupid people and we and
we sat around that person
and we were like, oh we
laughed.
Do you understand?  Do you understand
?  That means we're coming from you
.  Okay?
There is no quality greater
than that.  That's all.  If
everything is empty,
then everything is effective; if
nothing is empty, then nothing is
effective
.  But he said that he
said the opposite of what was said at the beginning of
this chapter.  And that man
said that the nature of emptiness has abandoned the Four Noble Truths
.
And if the Four Noble Truths had the nature of emptiness,
then they wouldn't be effective, right?  And
if they don't have the characteristic of zero, then
they are
ineffective.  Okay.  And sometimes you need to
remember
these verses.  And if you want to learn
Sanskrit, there is no
better Sanskrit than this book,
these verses.  Okay.  And I'm using
Dam's interpretations.   It was
written about 300 years
ago, and I will translate it if I
have the time, unless someone asks
me to do anything
else.
6.2. Okay. I think we'll have a Q&A session in
12 minutes, right?
Next
up is verse number 18.
This is
a very famous chapter in
the last 2000 years,
and
incidentally.  If someone were to ask you, "
What is the middle way?"  What is the Middle Way?  And
here is the answer.  What is the Middle Way
?  And here's the answer.  Is there anyone
better than Lord
Ngauna?  Let's talk about the middle
way.  This is a very famous poem
where Aagasuna explained
what the middle way is and he
spoke about what we call
dependence.  What is dependence?  If
everything comes from the seeds in
your mind.  And if I were to say that the
origin of dependence is something I
absolutely hate, hate, hate this very thing.  When
you talk about dependence, I hate
these things, but it's just that
everything comes from your mind,
how you treat
other people, and that
's dependent on your traditions,
and that's
nothingness.  Who said that?
Is it a fact?  No.
Nothingness is negation.  Nothingness is
negation.  Dependence is an
affirmative statement, while non-dependence is a
negative statement.  They come from the seeds in
your minds.  Tell me
what didn't work.  They
don't come from seeds
where nothingness is something that is
always absent
.  Technically speaking.  They are not the
same.  They are not the
same.  Depending on their nature, they are
not the
same.  Labeling and categorization are
manifestations of the middle way, created
from seeds in the mind
.  Is this a pen?   Is
it labeled as a pen
?  The labeling usually
means that the name is it, it is a
name.  Okay.  It's a name you stick
on a loaf of
bread, and it doesn't mean the middle way.  It
has it, it just has it, it just means it comes
from the seed in your mind.  It
is labeled by your minds.
And those labels have always been
practiced and applied in
those mental photographs.  The
seeds open up and
these pictures come out and it
covers
these things.  And I like to use two scoops of ice
cream.
Two scoops of ice cream and you cover
this with chocolate sauce, these two
scoops of ice cream, these images, these
images covering these, these images covering these,
this thing,
okay, they say that being labeled
means being labeled by
images in the mind, and that's
why the dog looks at it and says, "
I can chew on this car
."  Okay.  It seems very simple.  It's
too simple.  It's very easy.  It's
like Gesilla is trying to make
it easy.  But there isn't
any.  I didn't do that.
If the dog wants to chew on this
instead of writing a
letter, it proves the point and the pointlessness of the
pen, and you don't
need 2000 years of classical houses
.  If the dog sees
other things and
proves that it has a sense of self, that's all there is to it,
and it's very simple.  It's as
simple as that.  No one in the
universe can say that there isn't a
dog that looks like
that.  If the dog actually saw
something, it's
proven that the way it reacted was because
they chewed on it.  They didn't
write the
letter.  You don't need to turn on anything
else.  The fact that the dog
didn't see that it was a pen is
proof, and this is proof
that Buddhism is right, and this is proof that
it is proven that the dog is proven to be wrong.
There is one
thing I won't talk about politics
here.  The truth is, the pen comes from the
seed in your mind.  Okay.
And what is that circle, that last line, here
?  That is the middle way.  That is the middle
way.  Okay.  But here, both of them are on the right path
.  That is truly the middle
way.  It's the halfway point between
dependence and
nothingness.  And that is the highest school
of Buddhism.  There is nothing higher than that
.  And that is Buddhism that is used
for dissolution.  That is the path of
excess diamonds.  We have four minutes
left.  Those people with profound
Buddhist thought, could someone please tell me
what the next verse is?
You're right, absolutely right.  He used
the logic of his opponents
against them.  And that
is the style that Lord Nagatuna
always uses.   Okay
.  And listen to what I have to say to you two
.  He
used the same Sanskrit words that his
opponent had used the
first time.  OK.
And he said, "Okay, you know,
if things don't have a broad scope,
then everything will go
wrong."  And and in and the opponent
once said that if
it's
okay and he said okay, you know,
when I think about
it, if everything isn't empty,
then the whole thing will be
wrong.  He used the same words that his
opponent used against his opponent,
and he explained the
spiritual seed, and he explained the
pen and
you, and if everything is as
you
described, then there is no truth at
all.   There
is no "if" if there is no "
nothingness," then there are no Four Noble Truths,
you cannot relate these things
to the Four Noble Truths, and you cannot get
results. And if everything is
empty, we will have
problems. That's very cute, and that's
Naguna Ha's style
.  Okay.  Let's finish
this, and I know the Q&A is coming up soon
this first, and then I'll finish the
book.
Can you read the Tibetan text in the next picture
?
Gipsinh
kalau
hukum by
[music]
by the way
.  We
typed it, we typed the
classics using
Latin characters.  But why don't we
use Chinese words?
Because when we started
this project in
1983, all the computers that were
going to be used were based on
Latin languages, so we started
inputting data using
Latin.  And one weakness of the
Xuanzang Pagoda
is that the translators were
not familiar with
reading and found it very difficult to read the
texts on the wooden slabs,
and we had problems
with those slabs.
Optical
character recognition makes as many as a
type
who gson
choco what is
guru santia Deva it is just guru
Seva.  His name, his nickname, came about
because everyone in
his monastery thought he was very
lazy, a bad person, but in
reality, he was busy going
home to do
other activities that nobody
expected.  And he wrote one of the
greatest books ever
written, and I was very hesitant to take it
out of the question.  But
I didn't do that, and it was
the three locks 10, 11, and 12, and I was very
hesitant to take them out.
No one has written
greater books on the lifestyle of
a Bodhisattva than
Sentidava.  Okay.  And in those
ancient carvings it was called
Sund.  It's like he's very
proud of it.  Okay.  And you call me a
lazy man?  Okay.  Right
.  I'm lazy.  But you
guys don't have one thing you know absolutely nothing about
.  All of his work
is secret.  You know
...  Auna said
that if everything went the way
you wanted it to, if everything was
empty, then there would be no
body, and therefore no Bodhisattva way of life
.
Lord Nagatuna actually attacked the
opponent.  Okay.  Okay, you're right
.  If everything lacked
broad and unwavering support, then there would be no Three
Jewels (Buddha, Dharma, Sangha).  And because without the Three Jewels, there can be
no Buddha.  And if
everything isn't
empty, you can't become a
Buddha.  Therefore, you cannot
practice the paramitas badly, can you?
And even on this point, Lord Nagatuna
criticized his
opponent.  Okay.  And according to you, the six paramitas
were thrown out the window and
you don't need to hit them.
And when you see
this image, you will
remember that without emptiness, there would be
no Bodhisattvas, no Three
Jewels, and no one could become a Bodhisattva
.  You cannot practice,
you cannot practice Buddhism, you
cannot practice the paramitas.
If you don't understand
emptiness, and how emptiness makes them
perfect.  Okay.  And this is the final part.  This is the
last thing.  And now we'll do a
Q&A. These new books were written
by Rza.  Okay.  You should thank her
.  Thank you,
Rosa.  She did two really,
really good things.  She was responsible
for publishing the
Mn team's books, and they had about
four completed books, or 4 to 15
books, and no one in history had ever done
this before.
No one has done this in 600
years.  No one has done this like
we've been doing for 600 years.  And that's
fantastic.
And so many things gradually came about,
and we should thank Ra.  She has done
some amazing things,
and she has done two
amazing things.  And I worked with a
publisher in New York, and they had the
rights, and she bought the rights, and
we would have the right to
print our book
.  And because they still make money,
but they don't want to give
us the money, but we bought the
rights.   Okay
.  It's the 25th anniversary of the time I
wrote the book "Garden," the name of the
garden, the garden itself, and it's a
person, a very great angel,
about 20 to 30 years ago
when I translated the
fundamental teachings of
Buddhism in the Yoga Sutras, and we
had permission to republish
these books. This is the QR
Code, and we released the
hardcover book "Meditation on
Emptiness" by Venorebo
Bala, which includes all the
details about the
correct meditation techniques. Even if you haven't
read the sections on emptiness and the
second part on how to meditate,
and the teachings of Kamalasila
on how to meditate.   Okay
.  And I'm not advertising
anything here.  I'm not doing any
advertising.  I am pointing out that something
.
And Nagatuna said this at the very end, right here and at the
end of this chapter.  And he said
that if you truly understand
emptiness, you will understand the
seed.  If you are a master of
emptiness, you will understand
seeds.  And they came about, they
came from those famous statements.
An ancient text where
people liked to sing songs to the
Buddha to teach about
dependence.  He is very handsome.  He taught the
[musical] seed
and you know, emptiness is
in the
seed and there is a great
collection of songs that have been
offered to the Buddha that are like he is
so
great because he taught the
seeds and that is the
real seed and that and one
of the famous beautiful songs
is
Senadopha, the Buddha's teachings
on emptiness
in the form of the seed and there is
a translation
and commentary and GPSion will be
completed tomorrow.  Okay.  And you
need to be there, and you need to be
there.
He
was already in the
final paragraphs
and we were almost finished.  Okay.
And I think we'll need to
finish it
tomorrow.  And this is where it comes
from, from these verses,
from the final verses
in this chapter of
Nagona.  And it's very
appealing that this dependency is embracing
nothingness.  And if you really
understand them, you'll see they're
like a pair.  And he spoke
about
that.  Okay.  That's enough, let's stop here.   Okay
.
Q&A. Let's give it to whoever has a
microphone.  Okay.  Thank you, Gilla, for teaching.  Okay.
Thank you for coming
here.  Okay.  I think he was here when
ACI started a hundred years
ago.
I was thinking about the
truths of the law of cause and
effect.
I'm curious about what's going on
in the world.  How do we
think about the laws of cause and
effect?  It's like 2 + 2 =
4. How is that related?
And if we continue to think about
these facts, how do they
help
us?  Okay, I'll tell you what
I'm thinking.
When we read in Buddhism
that there are three ways to test
gold, we call them the three ways to test
gold, right?  And it took me a lot of
time to understand
these things, and I went back and forth
many times.
And back in the old days, when
you were buying a horse, and
the horse seller was okay, and you said, "
Okay, 400 or 390."
Okay.  What do you say it is called in Chinese
?  Before Alibay, the payment methods
through Alibay did not involve credit cards
, cash,
or gold coins.
And because there were no gold coins,
when you bought
horses you had to pay with corn, and
you
agreed.  And back in ancient times, you
could burn money just like you
burned grain.  And that's
how people in ancient times
offered
fire as a sacrifice.  I have a lot of faith in Buddhism and I
will burn money and make offerings to it.  And that is what is
called offering fire, the
meaning of offering
fire.  And when people start talking about
gold bars, and
those who aren't being
honest, 10 minutes later they're thinking about the three ways to
test gold.   "
Che" means to burn it, "ch" means to
cut it, "đ" means to
melt
it, how they establish the
truth, and that's the three-part test of
gold, and that's the tradition, okay, go
back to the ancient times, to the
ancient times of weighing horses,
one of the parts that determines whether it's
right or not must be
confirmed by your direct personal experience,
and it's very difficult because you haven't reached
that level yet, and it's called direct experience,
and in this case, there's
no direct professional experience
.  And the second step is the reverse:
checking.  And we open the box to see
what's inside.  Let's
cut open the gold bar and see what's
inside.  And this is considered to be
confirmed by logic.
And that's how it is, like in
Germany they say, that this is a
relationship between cause and effect.
And if you don't sow
apple seeds, you won't grow apples.   If
you
don't list it, forget about
religion,
and it won't make sense if
you don't grow chili peppers.  If you grow
chili peppers, you can also grow bananas
.  That was the second test
.  It means
to melt
it.  Okay.  And it's not encouraged
in the diamond business.  And
you and your friends don't want to
crush the diamonds to see if
they're real or
not.  What is it called?  It's
called permission.  One
right, that right, it's
kind of defined as a right,
that I followed the advice that
everything was good, and that's the best thing
you can say about the
rights, the powers that are allowed, but
the right is a bit
weak compared to logic.
And he said that I shouldn't kill
people because I wouldn't be able to come to a
conclusion.  And now I cannot
confirm that
.  Those are three ways to test gold.  If
you're looking for
someone you can trust, and that's
why it
takes a long time to
find a spiritual teacher,
and you have to test, test,
test, test, and then you can start
following them.  And that's what
Buddhism answers: there are three tests,
and you need to pass those three tests
.
And we say that it could be, it could be,
like, it could be true,
right?  Okay.  And the truth is,
I need to eat breakfast.  I don't know
what you guys are doing
.  Okay.  And the truth is, you need to
figure out whether I'm telling the truth or
not.  Okay.  Thank you.